Contact

nguyenhongky1998@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kynguyen98 (LinkedIn) svenikea.github.io (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Sonarqube

Grafana

Trivy

Certifications

English Proficiency Certificate Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Ky Nguyen

DevOps Engineer

Da Nang City, Vietnam

Summary

I am a dedicated and experienced DevOps professional with a strong passion for implementing efficient and scalable solutions in software development and IT operations. I have developed a comprehensive skill set encompassing areas such as continuous integration and deployment, infrastructure automation, cloud computing, and configuration management. My goal is to contribute my expertise to drive innovation and improve efficiency within organization.

Experience

TechSoft
DevOps Engineer
March 2023 - Present (2 years 1 month)
Da Nang City, Vietnam

Responsible for the operational effectiveness and efficiency

Result

- Optimized AWS infrastructure, cutting operational costs by 20% and boosting data warehouse performance for uninterrupted trading before market hours
- * Implementing GitOps with ArgoCD with Helm charts to automate and streamline Kubernetes deployments.
- * Leverage AWS Code Pipeline and Azure Pipeline to automate builds, tests, and deployments for multiple environments.
- Centralized monitoring dashboard with custom metrics via Grafana, Loki, and Lambda, significantly enhancing backend availability.
- Consulted clients on best AWS practices, swiftly addressing service disruptions with documented plans to uphold SLA.
- Creating a customer support portal enabling the QA team to efficiently track bugs and enhance productivity

Saigon Technology - Top Software Outsourcing Company in Vietnam DevOps Engineer June 2022 - March 2023 (10 months)

Page 1 of 2

Da Nang City, Vietnam

Managed Cloud infrastructure with IaC, provided DevOps consulting, optimized deployment with CI/CD, and integrated Agile methodology for efficiency

Result

- Advised clients on DevOps practices, ensuring PCI compliance
- Implemented Agile methodology in software development for faster development
- Established a zero-downtime deployment with CI/CD

Sun* Vietnam System Engineer October 2020 - June 2022 (1 year 9 months) Da Nang Metropolitan Area

Supervised on-premise, automated manual processes in both on-premises and Cloud platform with IaC

Result

- Led the initiative to transition legacy software to align with updated standards and needs
- Offered direction to the developer team in embracing DevOps principles, diminishing reliance on the Operations team
- Company's operational preparedness is ensured

Education

Danang University of Science and Technology
Engineer's degree, Embedded System · (September 2016 - May 2021)